<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alberto Arancibia</title><link>https://betoscopio.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Alberto Arancibia</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://betoscopio.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Website Reborn, again...</title><link>https://betoscopio.github.io/blog/20220202-website-reboot-again/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://betoscopio.github.io/blog/20220202-website-reboot-again/</guid><description>After a while with this website built with Jekyll I decided to make a new iteration of this blog. Some of the reasons is because Jekyll feels a bit dated to me and I did not enjoy that much to work with an application built with Ruby.
Recently, I have been trying a lot of things with Go(lang). One of the main pitch points of selling the language is what is made with it, and usually are mentioned Docker, Kubernetes, Prometheus, Caddy and of course Hugo.</description></item><item><title>"How to Manage a Remote Team" by GitLab</title><link>https://betoscopio.github.io/blog/2021-12-08-managing-remote-team/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 12:00:23 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://betoscopio.github.io/blog/2021-12-08-managing-remote-team/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week I finished the course &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/remote-team-management">How to Manage a Remote Team&lt;/a> created by GitLab/Coursera. I could get some consolidation of some practical knowledge that I already had and, of course, some great new information for me. Here are my views on it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DrupalCon Europe 2021</title><link>https://betoscopio.github.io/blog/2021-10-09-drupalcon-europe2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 12:00:23 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://betoscopio.github.io/blog/2021-10-09-drupalcon-europe2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>The last DrupalCon Europe just happened, the fourth Virtual DrupalCon, and possibly(?) the last one. Here is my take on this year’s DrupalCon Europe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Restarting the blog</title><link>https://betoscopio.github.io/blog/2021-10-08-blog-restart/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://betoscopio.github.io/blog/2021-10-08-blog-restart/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is just a testing post for the blog section.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://betoscopio.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://betoscopio.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hi, I am Alberto Arancibia You can find me at:
Github Twitter LinkedIn Drupal Software developer from Santiago, Chile, where I work doing development, software architecture and infraestructure configuration, I have a degree in Computer Science.
With more than 10 years of experience doing web related work, I have a focus on build maintainble, compatible and upgradable software. Linux user since Firefox was a new thing.
I have been involved in the Drupal community for about 10 years, have organized local Meetups and participated in many Drupal Events, here are some of my [talks]({% link talks.</description></item><item><title>Talks</title><link>https://betoscopio.github.io/talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://betoscopio.github.io/talks/</guid><description>My presentations in different conferences and meetups
Charla UNAP - Informática 2019: Abrazando el cambio, adaptandose a la evolución del desarrollo web Git Workshop UNAP - Informática 2019: Introducción a Git DrupalCamp São Paulo 2017 (second day keynote): Embracing the change, adapting to web development evolution Drupal Chile Meetup, 22 de Noviembre de 2016: Introducción a Composer Drupal Chile Meetup, 14 de Septiembre de 2016: Contribuyendo a Drupal Drupal Camp Costa Rica 2015: Actualiza tu webstack Drupal Summit Latino 2013, Loja Ecuador: Introducción a Drupal PHP está mejorando</description></item><item><title>Tools</title><link>https://betoscopio.github.io/tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://betoscopio.github.io/tools/</guid><description>A place to reference some random code, tools, snipets or my study notes. Most of this is WIP and should be considered as a raw version made public for my quick access or in case could be useful to someone.
A dockerized Jupyter environment Notas Kubernetes (Spanish) PHP Docker Files Not mine, but favourite Awesome Python Awesome Go Awesome Compose Jeff Geerling&amp;rsquo;s Kubernetes 101 Pelado Nerd Repo (Spanish)</description></item></channel></rss>